Rafat Anwar Munshi

Full Stack Developer

🗣 Mumbai, India 🛮 munshi.rafat07@gmail.com 📞 +917500602103 🕠 github.com/rafatmunshi

in linkedin.com/in/rafatmunshi/

Profile

Web Applications Developer with 5+ years of relevant experience developing Full Stack applications in the Technology, E-commerce and Education Industry. For me, technology is a tool leveraged to deliver on Business requirements and User Experience. I find satisfaction in writing clean, tested and quality code. My current focus is learning and acing challenging work.

Professional Experience

07/2012 -11/2014

IT Engineer, Cisco Systems

Business Applications Developer

Cisco Developer Network- www.developer.cisco.com ☐ (~1 year)

Role: Individual Contributor (Team size- 8)

- Improved user experience by working closely with the team in the US to understand requirements, make Technical Design Document and develop quality code followed by unit testing.
- Developed enhancements on existing functionalities for the large-scale application.
- Built a Java API to upload videos to Cisco's video sharing platform as a reusable component for 100s of Cisco Engineers.

Tech: Liferay, Spring portlet MVC, Quartz Scheduler

Delivery Collaboration Portal- www.dcp.cisco.com ☐ (~1 year)

Role: Individual Contributor (Team size-7)

- Actively contributed in a high performing team under the Agile process, to understand requirement stories and follow clean coding practice with a test-driven approach for the complex application.
- Created an interactive webpage that automated tasks in the application workflow thereby improving the efficiency of users.
- Mentored 2 junior Developers to quickly overcome gaps and start contributing to critical applications.

Tech: Java, Junit, Oracle DB, JQuery

01/2015 -06/2016

Web Consultant, Maroof Consultancy

Swag of India. Role: Core team member (Team size- 6)

- Involved in ecommerce website development and analytics for UAE and India based markets
- Established Pixel Perfect UI Design and Internationalization
- Responsible for API integrations and website traffic analytics report generation
- · Worked collaboratively with marketing, operations, and customer connection to keep up the product growth which increased website traffic and sales by 30%

Tech: PHP WordPress- WooCommerce, MySQL, Google Analytics, MailChimp

09/2016 – present

Full Stack Applications Developer & Instructor, AMU

Technical Assistant (Computer) - (1 year 9 months relevant as a Full Stack Engineer)

Internal Quality Assurance Cell (IQAC) Role: Project Lead (Team size-4)

- Owned end-to-end deliverables individually of software applications from feature discussions, requirement gathering, release milestone planning to designing then coding, testing, debugging, documentation, deployment and maintenance.
- Suggested practical and scalable solutions which improved efficiency of processes of a 15 persons team by more than 80%.
- Became first point of contact for user interaction for software adoption by the 2000+ users.
- Reduced requests to the Director, IQAC by 75% by becoming subject matter expert and first point of contact for report generation for the National Assessment and Accreditation Council (NAAC)

Other responsibilities (2 years 6 months)

• Boosted practical learning of 600+ students with improved Curriculum, Guidance and Teaching methodologies for Programming and Web Technology projects

11/2020 –

Software Engineer, Recursive Lambda

01/2021

DevOps Engineer

- Setup infrastructure on Google Cloud Platform using Infrastructure As Code (Terraform) to run a Python Flask application for exposing infrastructure related information.
- Containerised the application using Docker.
- Built CI/CD pipeline on Gitlab to deploy on different environments.

07/2020 –

Online Course Instructor, Skill Lync

present

Content Creator

• Developed Industry relevant Full Stack Technology Course content and supported students technically to be job ready for Front End Development, Data Structures and Algorithms using Java and Python, Advanced Databases, Back-End programming for Java Web Applications

Projects

08/2020 -

Inventory Management System (~4 months)

04/2021

Semi-automatic Web system that manages and stores information on inventory of the college.

Tech: React.js, Node.js

12/2019 -

Students Information Portal (~4 months)

03/2020

Web System for registration and storage of students' personal, admissions and fees detail with live status tracking.

Tech: Spring Boot, Hibernate, MySQL, ES6

08/2019 –

Grievance Redressal System (~4 months)

11/2019

Web system to track, notify and store time-bound grievances of various stakeholders of the university

Tech: Java, MySQL, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap

02/2019 - Students Feedback Portal (~6 months)

07/2019 Web System for the university to gain and analyse feedback from students and faculty for

their subjects and departments.

Tech: Spring MVC, MongoDB, Google Charts API

10/2018 – Faculty Information Portal (~4 months)

01/2019 Centralised Web system to store details of faculty members, their subjects, classes and

attendance.

Tech: PHP, MySQL

Skills

Java Frontend

Spring Boot, Spring MVC, Hibernate, Liferay, JSP, React.js (basic), HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap,

Servlets, JDBC, JUnit JavaScript ES6, jQuery

Database Others

MySQL, MongoDB, Oracle RESTful Web Services, JSON, XML, PHP,

WordPress, Algorithms, Data Structures

Version control

Git, SVN Build
Maven

DevOps (basics)

Python, Bash Scripting, GitLab CI/CD, Google Knowledge of

Cloud Platform, Terraform, Docker Systems Design, Object Oriented Programming,

Design Patterns

Certificates

Oracle certified Java Associate (OCJA)

Oracle certified Associate (OCA) - SQL

2012 Level 1, 2012

Education

2012 Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech), Veermata Jijabai Technological Institute (V.J.T.I)

Mumbai, India CGPA- 8.5/10

2008 Higher Secondary Education (H.S.C)

Mumbai, India Percentage- 94.5%

Third rank in Mumbai, India